Merrill Moore Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Merrill Moore Papers 1904-1979 1928-1957
MSS33373
Moore, Merrill, 1903-1957
131,750 items
504 containers plus 86 oversize
234 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Psychiatrist and poet. Diaries, correspondence, notebooks, biographical material, family papers, genealogical records, literary papers, scrapbooks, printed matter, and other papers relating to Moore's career as a psychiatrist and poet.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Adler, Alexandra, 1901-2001--Correspondence.; Bock, Arlie V. (Arlie Vernon), 1888-1984--Correspondence.; Cobb, Stanley, 1887-1968--Correspondence.; Davidson, Donald, 1893-1968--Correspondence.; Fitts, Dudley, 1903-1968--Correspondence.; Moore family.; Moore, Adam G. N.--Correspondence.; Moore, Merrill, 1903-1957.; Murray, Henry A. (Henry Alexander), 1893-1988. Henry A. Murray papers.; Overholser, Winfred, 1892-1964--Correspondence.; Ransom, John Crowe, 1888-1974--Correspondence.; Sachs, Hanns, 1881-1947--Correspondence.; Solomon, Harry C. (Harry Caesar), 1889-1982--Correspondence.; Tate, Allen, 1899-1979--Correspondence.; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977--Correspondence.; Wells, Frederic Lyman, 1884-1964--Correspondence.
Organizations
Boston City Hospital.; Harvard University. Harvard Psychological Clinic.; United States. Army--Medical care.; Washingtonian Hospital (Boston, Mass.)
Subjects
Alcoholism.; American literature.; American poetry.; Americans--China.; Bromides.; Drug abuse.; Jews--Germany.; Literature.; Medicine--Practice--Massachusetts--Boston.; Military psychiatry.; Neurology.; Poetry.; Psychiatry.; Sonnets, American.; Suicide.; Syphilis.; War--Psychological aspects.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945--Medical care.; World War, 1939-1945--New Zealand.; World War, 1939-1945--Oceania.
Occupations
Poets.; Psychiatrists.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Merrill Moore, psychiatrist and poet, were given to the Library of Congress by the Moore family in 1937-1972. Additions were given by Adam G. N. Moore in 1979 and Henry A. Murray in 1984.
Additional Guides
In 1972 the Library published Merrill Moore, a Register of His Papers in the Library of Congress, which includes an index of selected correspondents. A copy of the index is also available in the Manuscript Division Reading Room and as a PDF document.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Some photographs, drawings, and prints have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. Recordings have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the Merrill Moore Papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Merrill Moore are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1903, Sept. 11 Born, Columbia, Tenn.
1924 B.A., Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tenn.
1928 M.D., Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tenn.
1928 1929 Intern, St. Thomas Hospital, Nashville, Tenn.
1930 Married Ann Leslie Nichol
1930 1931 Teaching fellow in neurology, Harvard Medical School, Cambridge, Mass. Neurological house officer and resident neurological physician, Boston City Hospital, Boston, Mass.
1931 1932 Assistant in neuropathology, Harvard Medical School, Cambridge, Mass.
1932 1935 Assistant physician, Boston Psychopathic Hospital, Boston, Mass.
1933 1934 Graduate assistant, Psychiatric Clinic, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Mass.
1935 Began private practice in Boston, Mass.
1936 1942 Research fellow in psychiatry, Harvard Medical School, Cambridge, Mass.
1942 1946 Military service, mainly in Southwest Pacific and China
1947 Resumed private practice
1957, Sept. 20 Died, Quincy, Mass.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Merrill Moore (1903-1957) span the period 1904-1979, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the years 1928-1957. The collection consists primarily of correspondence and writings, supplemented by diaries, notebooks, scrapbooks, printed matter, clippings, and miscellany. Documenting Moore's career as a psychiatrist and poet, the papers are organized into nine series: Diaries, Reminiscences, and Notebooks; Family Correspondence and Special File; General Correspondence; Subject File; Literary File; Scrapbooks (Oversize); Clippings; Miscellany; and Addition.
Moore made sporadic efforts to keep a diary, but his notes are extensive only for the period he spent in New Zealand during World War II. These notes are accompanied by memoranda and miscellaneous items that he collected in anticipation of writing a book based on his experiences. This material, which documents his service as a medical officer as well as his literary activities and plans, is most exhaustive for November 1942, when he sailed from San Francisco to Auckland, New Zealand, and for June 1943, when he made a brief visit to Guadalcanal.
Material concerning Moore's medical career, which spanned almost three decades, is contained in the General Correspondence and Subject File series. Graduating from Vanderbilt Medical School in 1928, Moore served his internship in Nashville and then entered an extensive period of training in neurology and psychiatry in the Boston area. During the course of his training, Moore came into contact with several leading neurologists and psychiatrists, including Alexandra Adler, Arlie V. Bock, Stanley Cobb, Winfred Overholser, Hanns Sachs, Harry C. Solomon, and Frederic Lyman Wells. All are represented by correspondence.
Moore also devoted much time to original research, particularly in areas directly related to mental illness and neurological disease. His extensive writings on the subjects of alcoholism, suicide, syphilis, drug addiction, and related topics are located in the Subject File. Four years of military service in the Pacific theater failed to dampen his productivity. His work in the areas of shell shock and alcoholism among military personnel, as well as his efforts to encourage and improve neurological services in military hospitals, is amply represented in both series.
Other subjects in the papers include Moore's efforts in 1938-1940 to aid Jewish doctors who were fleeing Nazi Germany. Moore's role as a consultant in 1940-1941 with companies making bromides, as well as controversies concerning the products' effectiveness, is also documented, especially in correspondence with Walter Compton (1912-1955) and George Ross Veazey in the Subject File series. The papers also contain substantial material relating to Moore's tour of duty in China in 1946 and correspondence in subsequent years with friends who remained in China or were deeply concerned about conditions there.
In the tradition of Oliver Wendell Holmes and William Carlos Williams, Moore coupled his medical career with an equally successful literary career. He derived much of his early interest in literature from his father, John Trotwood Moore, a poet, novelist, essayist, and historian. While still in high school, Moore developed his lifelong enthusiasm for the sonnet as a medium of expression. Soon after entering Vanderbilt University, he joined a group of fellow students and some of their teachers who were to form one of the most distinctive and cohesive literary groups of the twentieth century. Adopting the name Fugitives, the group made its contribution through the pages of The Fugitive (1922-1925), a magazine of verse. As a contributor to the magazine, Moore first revealed the propensity for experimentation and innovation that would mark his subsequent work and lead his biographer to characterize his poetry as “an essentially new and a highly significant experiment.” [1] At the same time, he cemented his commitment to sonnets.
[1] Henry Willis Wells, Poet and Psychiatrist: Merrill, M.D. (New York: Twayne [1955]), 2.
In the following years, Moore became something of a literary phenomenon by writing over fifty thousand sonnets, only a small portion of which were published. A large part of this production is represented in the Literary File. The series includes drafts, revisions, and fragments, as well as complete sonnets, and provides a broad base for a full analysis of his verse. The wide range of literary correspondence in the General Correspondence and Subject File series serves as a valuable supplement to the work itself. Moore corresponded with numerous literary figures, including Donald Davidson, Dudley Fitts, John Crowe Ransom, Allen Tate, and Louis Untermeyer.
The Addition to the papers contains family and general correspondence and research material for a project Moore conducted at the Harvard Psychology Clinic. Included are outlines, drafts, and supplementary research, 1954-1975, for the publication of a book. Interviews were conducted with Moore by Christiana D. Morgan. Excerpts from these interviews are scattered throughout the Addition as well as earlier sessions conducted with Robert N. Wilson, and research notes of Ina Mae Greer. Also included is a typescript of the intended publication, designated second version: “Merrill Moore, M.D. The Creative Process in a Living Poet: A Study of the Genesis of Certain Forms of the Imagination.”
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in nine series:
Diaries, Reminiscences, and Notebooks, 1920-1957
Family Correspondence and Special File, 1904-1958
General Correspondence, 1914-1957
Subject File, circa 1920-1957
Literary File, circa 1923-1958
Scrapbooks (Oversize), 1911-1948
Clippings, circa 1920-1957
Miscellany, 1920-1957
Addition, 1930-1979
Container List
- Diaries, Reminiscences, and Notebooks, 1920-1957 (Box A1-A8)
  Diaries, diary notes, reminiscences, and notebooks.
  Organized into three groupings: bound diaries and reminiscences, unbound diary notes, and notebooks.
  - Bound diaries and reminiscences (Box A1)
    - Diary
      - 1920, July
      - 1928, Jan.-Feb.
      - 1929, July-Aug.
    - Notebook entitled “Things To Remember,” containing diary entries, notes, clippings, and cards, circa 1943, July-1945, June
    - Scrapbooks for son Leslie, describing in photographs and prose a trip in June 1943 to Guadalcanal, 1944
    - Scrapbook for daughter Hester, describing in photographs and prose a trip in June 1943 to Guadalcanal, 1944 (Box A2)
    - Diary, 1945, May
    - Notebook of autobiographical notes, including recollections of his youth in Nashville, Tenn., and notes for further writing, circa 1945.
  - Unbound diary notes (Box A3)
    - 1920
    - 1928
    - 1942, Nov.
    - 1942, Dec.-1943, May (Box A4)
    - 1943, June-1945, Apr. (Box A5)
    - 1947-1956 (Box A6)
  - Notebooks (Box A7-A8)
    - Address books, composition books, memorandum books, dictation books, and bound lecture notes, circa 1920-1957
- Family Correspondence and Special File, 1904-1958 (Box B1-B52)
  Correspondence, clipping book, diary notes, transcripts, and printed matter.
  Organized into two groupings: family correspondence and special file.
  - Family correspondence (Box B1)
    - Barnes, Bess Daniel
    - Cheek, Hettie, 1931-1941, undated
    - Cheek, Hettie, case (Box B2)
      - Abstract
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1938, 1954-1957
      - Transcripts
        - 1934-1936
        - 1937-1944 (Box B3)
        - 1945-1948 (Box B4)
        - 1949-1951 (Box B5)
        - 1952-1954 (Box B6)
    - Cheek, Huldah
    - Cheek, Leslie, Jr.
    - Cheek, Leslie, Sr.
    - Cheek, Mabel W.
    - Cheek, Menifee R.
      - 1950, 1954
      - 1955-1957 (Box B7)
    - Cheek, Will T.
    - Cole, Helen Moore
      - 1934-1939
      - 1940-1950 (Box B8)
      - 1951-1957, undated (Box B9)
    - Cole, Mary Bass (Box B10)
    - Cole, Whitefoord R., Jr.
      - 1929-1942
      - 1943-1953 (Box B11)
      - 1954-1957, undated (Box B12)
    - Cole, Whitefoord R., III, 1939-1957, undated
    - Daniel, Mrs. H. Clay
    - Kapp, Ella Lu
    - Merrill, Pearl D.
    - Moore, Adam G. N.
      - 1936-1953
      - 1954-1958, undated (Box B13)
      - Miscellany
    - Moore, Ann Leslie (Box B14)
      - 1930-1943
      - 1942-1943, correspondence and clipping book (oversize) (Box OV B15)
      - 1944 (Box B16)
        - Jan.-June
        - July (Box B17)
        - Aug. (Box B18)
        - Sept. (Box B19)
        - Oct. (Box B20)
        - Nov. (Box B21)
        - Dec. and no month or day (Box B22)
      - 1945, Jan.-Apr. (Box B23)
      - 1945, May-1946, Apr. (Box B24)
      - 1946, June-1957, undated (Box B25)
      - Miscellany
    - Moore, Helen (Box B26)
    - Moore, Hester
    - Moore, John (died 1904)
    - Moore, John Trotwood (1858-1929)
    - Moore, John T.
      - (born 1933), 1936-1951
      - 1952-1957, undated (Box B27)
    - Moore, John T., 1952-1957, undated
    - Moore, Leslie
    - Moore, Mary Daniel (Mrs. John Trotwood Moore), 1923-1930
    - Moore, Mary Daniel (Box B28)
      - 1931-1937
      - 1938-1939 (Box B29)
      - 1940-1941 (Box B30)
      - 1942-1944 (Box B31)
      - 1945-1948 (Box B32)
      - 1949-1952 (Box B33)
      - 1953-1957, undated (Box B34)
      - Miscellany
      - Transcript of a conversation with Merrill Moore
    - Nichol, Adam G. (Box B35)
      - 1929
      - 1930-1931, book of letters to Ann Leslie Nichol Moore and Merrill Moore
      - 1931-1941, undated
      - Miscellany
    - Nichol, Ann Leslie (Box B36)
      - 1929, Jan.-Sept.
      - 1929, Oct.-1930, Feb. (Box B37)
      - 1930 (Box B38)
        - Mar.-July
        - July-Aug., undated (Box B39)
    - Nichol, Bertha Cheek
    - Whitney, Joel M., family
    - Whitney, Mary Daniel Moore
  - Special file (Box B40)
    - Adler, Alexandra
    - Adler, Alfred
    - Autobiographical reminiscences, Merrill Moore
    - Case material, miscellaneous (Box B41)
    - Case summaries, World War II
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous
      - 1923, 1930-1942
      - 1943-1957, undated (Box B42)
    - Diary notes
      - 1944
      - 1945, Jan. 3-Apr. 26 (Box B43)
      - 1945, Apr. 27-1946, Feb. 10 (Box B44)
      - 1946, Feb. 11-1954, June 30, undated (Box B45)
    - Depuy, Trevor N. (Box B46)
    - Enters, Angna
    - Forbes, F. Murray, Jr.
    - McClure, Robert B.
      - 1947-1950
      - 1951, 1957, undated (Box B47)
      - Printed matter
    - Morgan, Christiana D., and Henry Murray, project of
      - Correspondence, 1957 See also Containers J4-J8, Research material
      - Transcripts of Merrill Moore's interviews with, 1954-1956
    - Murray, Henry A., Jr., and Robert N. Wilson, project of, 1950-1952 See also Containers J4-J8, Research material
    - Sachs, Hanns (Box B48)
    - Spack, Allan
      - 1946-1950
      - 1951-1957, undated (Box B49)
    - Starr, Alfred
    - Starr, Milton (Box B50)
      - 1936-1945
      - 1947-1953 (Box B51)
      - 1955-1957, undated (Box B52)
    - Theatre Guild “picnic” statements
    - Wedemeyer, Albert C.
      - Correspondence
      - Miscellany
      - Printed matter
- General Correspondence, 1914-1957 (Box C1-C69)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, supplemented by memoranda, two bound volumes of acknowledgments, and miscellaneous enclosures and attachments.
  Arranged chronologically by month with the bound volumes at the end.
  - 1914 (Box C1)
  - 1922-1933
  - 1934-1936 (Box C2)
  - 1937, Jan.-Nov. (Box C3)
  - 1937, Dec.-1938, Apr. (Box C4)
  - 1938 (Box C5)
    - May-July
    - Aug.-Oct. (Box C6)
  - 1938, Nov.-1939, Jan. (Box C7)
  - 1939, Feb.-Aug. (Box C8)
  - 1939, Sept.-1940, Feb. (Box C9)
  - 1940, Mar.-Sept. (Box C10)
  - 1940, Oct.-1941, Mar. (Box C11)
  - 1941, Apr.-Nov. (Box C12)
  - 1941, Dec.-1942, Mar. (Box C13)
  - 1942 (Box C14)
    - Apr.-May
    - May (Box C15)
    - June (Box C16)
    - June-July (Box C17)
    - July-Aug. (Box C18)
    - Aug.-Sept. (Box C19)
    - Sept.-Oct. (Box C20)
    - Oct.-Dec. (Box C21)
  - 1943, Dec.-1943-Mar. (Box C22)
  - 1943 (Box C23)
    - Apr.-May
    - June-Aug. (Box C24)
    - Sept.-Oct. (Box C25)
    - Nov.-Dec. (Box C26)
  - 1943, Dec.-1944, Feb. (Box C27)
  - 1944 (Box C28)
    - Mar.-May
    - May-Aug. (Box C29)
    - Sept.-Oct. (Box C30)
    - Nov.-Dec. (Box C31)
  - 1944, Dec.-1945, Feb. (Box C32)
  - 1945 (Box C33)
    - Mar.-June
    - June-July (Box C34)
    - Aug.-Sept. (Box C35)
  - 1945, Oct.-1946, Jan. (Box C36)
  - 1946 (Box C37)
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-Apr. (Box C38)
    - May-July (Box C39)
    - Aug.-Nov. (Box C40)
  - 1946, Dec.-1947, Jan. (Box C41)
  - 1947 (Box C42)
    - Feb.-Mar.
    - Apr.-May (Box C43)
    - May-July (Box C44)
    - Aug.-Sept. (Box C45)
    - Oct.-Nov. (Box C46)
  - 1947, Dec.-1948, Feb. (Box C47)
  - 1948 (Box C48)
    - Mar.-Apr.
    - May-June (Box C49)
    - July-Aug. (Box C50)
    - Sept.-Oct. (Box C51)
  - 1948, Nov.-1949, Jan. (Box C52)
  - 1949 (Box C53)
    - Feb.-Mar.
    - Apr.-July (Box C54)
    - Aug.-Oct. (Box C55)
  - 1949, Nov.-1950, Feb. (Box C56)
  - 1950, Mar.-1951, Jan. (Box C57)
  - 1951, Feb.-July (Box C58)
  - 1951, Aug.-Jan. 1952 (Box C59)
  - 1952 (Box C60)
    - Feb.-Aug.
    - Sept.-Nov. (Box C61)
  - 1952, Dec.-1953, Feb. (Box C62)
  - 1953 (Box C63)
    - Mar.-May
    - June-Sept. (Box C64)
    - Oct.-Dec. (Box C65)
  - 1954 (Box C66)
    - Jan.-Nov.
  - 1954, Dec.-1957, Sept. (Box C67)
  - Bound volume of acknowledgments of Moore's article on Dr. Morton Prince, 1938, Aug.-1939, Jan. (Oversize) (Box OV C68)
  - Bound volume of acknowledgments of Moore's Christmas circular letter, 1943, Nov.-1944, May (Oversize) (Box OV C69)
- Subject File, circa 1920-1957 (Box D1-D219)
  Correspondence, memoranda, writings, notes, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person or organization, subject, or type of material.
  - “A” miscellaneous, 1954-1957 (Box D1)
  - Abbott, Mary Ogden
    - Correspondence, 1936-1942
    - Interview (Box D2)
    - Clippings
  - Adler, Alfred, lecture on
  - Adolescence
  - Age Center of New England
  - Aiken, Conrad, correspondence, 1953
  - Alcohol
    - 1934-1939
    - 1934-1939 (Box D3)
    - 1940
      - Jan.-July
      - Aug.-Dec. (Box D4)
    - 1941-1946 (Box D5)
    - 1947-1952 (Box D6)
    - Abstracts (Box D7)
    - Alcohol education
    - Alcohol and crime
    - Alcoholic avitaminosis
    - Alcoholic Consultation Bureau
    - Alcoholic mysticism
    - Alcoholic survey of Boston, Mass., 1937
    - Alcoholism
    - Alcoholism at the Boston City Hospital, Boston, Mass. (Box D8)
    - Alcoholism movie
    - Alcoholism slides
    - Alcoholism
      - Public health problem
      - Medical problem
      - Definition
      - Determination
      - Diagnosis
      - Radio program
      - Study of
      - Alcoholism project
      - Allied Youth
      - American Business Men's Research Foundation
      - American Public Health Association
      - Anti-Saloon League of New Jersey
      - Anti-Saloon League of Rhode Island
    - Alcoholism and ethics (Box D9)
    - Alcoholism and public opinion
    - Alcoholism and psychobiopathic traits
    - Alcoholism and suicide
    - Alcoholism and the user of drugs
    - Article for New England Journal of Medicine, 1952
    - Bloomberg, Wilfred
    - Book review
    - Boston City Hospital Advisory Committee, Boston, Mass.
    - Clark, Byron B.
    - Clark, Robert A.
    - Clotting
    - Conference of hospital superintendents
    - Connecticut Temperance Foundation
    - Davis, Maxine
    - Delirium tremens
    - Dynes, John B.
    - Executive Committee, Research Council on Problems of Alcohol
    - Expenses
    - Further work
    - Gray, M. Geneva
    - “Green Lights to Health Program”
    - Guinness (A.) Son & Co.
    - Gutherie and Dayton, article by
    - Hospital reports
    - Jamaica ginger paralysis (Box D10)
    - Labeling
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts re alcoholism and suicide
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts re alcoholism and suicide (Box D11-D15)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts re alcoholism and suicide (Box D16)
    - Miscellany
    - Newspaper clippings
    - Newspaper clippings (Box D17)
    - Norfolk County Medical Society
    - Prevalence of alcoholism
    - References on suicide
    - Reference on suicide (Box D18)
    - Special articles
    - Statistics
    - Suggestions
    - Summary of 135 records at Boston City Hospital
    - Survey of suicide attempts
    - Women's Christian Temperance Union
  - Alexander, Leo, paper, 1951-1957 (Box D19)
  - Allen, David
  - Allen, J. Owen
  - American Board of Psychiatry and Neurology
  - American Iris Society
  - American Journal of Psychiatry
  - American Malacological Union
  - American Medical Association, paper, 1955-1957
  - American Museum Shop
  - American Neurological Association, 1942, 1952-1955 (Box D20)
  - American Psychiatric Association, 1941, 1952-1957
  - American Psychopathological Association
    - 1934-1939, 1952-1956
    - 1957 (Box D21)
  - American Psychosomatic Society
  - Anderson, Lee
  - Andoska, John B.
  - “Apologia, ”material for second printing
  - Appointments, 1952
  - Arcano, John
  - Armed forces
    - Fort Devens, Mass.
    - Fort Dix, N.J.
    - Fort Jay, N.Y.
    - Fort Monmouth, N. J.
  - Armed Forces Society of Medical Consultants
  - Armstrong, George E.
  - Armstrong, Phyllis E.
  - Association for the Advancement of Psychotherapy
  - Associated Medical Psychiatrists
  - Atlantic Monthly
  - Audubon Society
  - “B” miscellaneous (Box D22)
    - 1936-1942
    - 1936-1956 (Box D23)
    - 1957 (Box D24)
  - Baldwin, Maitland
  - Barnes, Bess Daniel
  - Barr, Mrs. Thomas C.
  - Barrett, David C., 1952-1957
  - Barsis, Olga and Max
  - Basham, Daisy (Box D25)
  - Basler, Roy P., 1952-1957
  - Bauer, W. W.
  - Baughan, Denver
  - Beale, John C.
  - Beaver School reading list
  - Becker, Samuel
  - Berliner, Barnett
  - Berlitz School of Languages
  - Berry, Agnes E.
  - Beth Israel Hospital, New York, N.Y.
  - Bethurum, Dorothy
  - Bibliography
  - Biographical material
  - Biographical material (Box D26-D27)
  - Blake, Sara (Box D28)
  - Blanchard, Harold H.
  - Bleuler, Manfred
  - Block, Mrs. Leonard W.
  - Blue Cross-Blue Shield
  - Board of the International Rescue Committee
  - Boats
  - Book reviews
    - 1955
    - Boston Medical Library, Boston, Mass.
    - Medical books
    - Nonmedical
    - Owens, Olga
    - Owens, Olga (Box D29)
  - Book reviews of Merrill Moore's poetry
  - Books, children four and five years
  - Books ordered, 1953-1954
  - Bookshop for Boys and Girls
  - Bosquet, Alain
  - Boston City Hospital, Boston, Mass. (Box D30)
    - “A” miscellaneous
    - Abbott, John A.
    - Acknowledgments and requests
    - Alcohol
    - Alcoholism study
    - Alcoholism
      - Ideas on
      - Lectures on
      - Notes on
      - Papers on
      - Questionnaire
      - References
      - Statistics
      - Treatment
    - Alcoholism and suicide
    - Alexander, Leo, 1937-1940 (Box D31)
    - Anamnesis
    - Andover Newton Theological School, Newton, Mass.
    - Appointments
    - Average length of hospitalization
    - “B” miscellaneous, 1935-1941
    - Beardsley, Walter R.
    - Biographical and bibliographical research in Boston, Mass.
    - Blotner, Harry
    - Boole, Ella A.
    - Bowman, Karl M.
    - Branham, V. C.
    - British Journal of Inebriety
    - Bullard, Ellen
    - Burwell, C. Sidney
    - “C” miscellaneous, 1935-1941 (Box D32)
    - Callahan, Roy H.
    - Capudine Chemical Co.
    - Clinic at Boston City Hospital
    - Cobb, Stanley
    - “D” miscellaneous, 1935-1941
    - Daily average number of patients, 1864-1934
    - Day, Hilbert F.
    - Dayton, Neil A.